<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: My Life | My Personal Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/categories/my-life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-22T09:43:14+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Budi Ariyanto]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moinmoin Wiki Engine]]></title>
    <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2012/02/08/moinmoin-wiki-engine/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-08T22:15:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2012/02/08/moinmoin-wiki-engine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
This is my first post at 2012. I want to get used to post articles at this blog again, beside my activities at the office. At this post, I want to share about a wiki engine that I currently interested in. It is named <a href="http://moinmo.in/" target="_blank">moinmoin</a>. It is not a new wiki engine and has already well known at world wild. This wiki engine is developed using <a href="http://python.org/" target="_blank">python</a> programming language. I love this wiki engine because this wiki engine is well documented, easy to setup, easy to use and it has many features, including but not limited to:<br /><ol><li>Easy wiki syntax.</li><li>Runs at any web server such as <a href="http://httpd.apache.org/" target="_blank">apache</a>, <a href="http://nginx.org/" target="_blank">nginx</a> and moinmoin stand alone web server(using python). But if you want to use apache or nginx, you need <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_Server_Gateway_Interface" target="_blank">wsgi</a> or <a href="http://www.fastcgi.com/drupal/" target="_blank">fast-cgi </a>module for the respective webserver. Don't use cgi since it's slow.</li><li>Macros. -- I love the macro that help create the table of contents :)</li><li>Auto numbering.</li><li>Easy leveling the depth of item/numbered list.</li><li>Private sub page.</li><li>It's content saved in plain text format. It means, save harddisk space and light weight.</li><li>Many plugins/addons. </li></ol>Currently I'm beginning to use moinmoin for works on any non-source code documentation at the office collaborate with my partners. Since it runs on web browser, everyone can read it. Trust me, it's fun. And it's even more fun if you combine moinmoin with <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/" target="_blank">dropbox</a>! :D</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Next Distro: Arch Linux]]></title>
    <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2011/11/07/my-next-distro-arch-linux/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-07T23:46:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2011/11/07/my-next-distro-arch-linux</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Slackware is my favourite linux distro since approximately 4.5 years ago. It brings so many useful experience to me at the very beginning I learn linux in early 2008. I still remember how I confuse because there are no desktop environment at the startup, and then I realize that there is one "magic command" that change everything. The <b>startx</b>. LOL .. And then I learn how to get connected to the internet using wireless network, configuring sound card, installing video driver, configuring xorg server, mounting removable disks, compile application from source tarball and slackware package manager, inserting and removing kernel modules, and many more... At the end, Slackware makes me understand how linux look like and how it works. Thanks to Patrick Volkerding who create and mantain this great distro until now.<br />These days, I try to take a new challenge. I want to switch the distro that I used everyday. But I didn't find any distro until I try Arch Linux. At first, I try Ubuntu 11.10 "Oneiric Ocelot" that has package manager that resolve dependency automatically based on the repository. I think it's very useful since make the user more productive with no more searching the package dependency to just install one package. Slackware don't have this feature and I think that's Slackware cons. For example, I have to compile and install 42 dependency package by myself for one vlc package with complete feature. Pheww... Ubuntu is a great distro too, since I like the font in Ubuntu that very readable. easy installing package and almost all configuration done in GUI. But after all, I think it becomes not flexible and I cannot control all the system. The configurations are like totally recreated(ex: no /etc/inittab), so when I use Ubuntu, I just only learn Ubuntu. In addition, there is new desktop environment in Ubuntu called Unity, which is just graduate and I think not stable yet. The Unity cannot be configured easily except compiz-config-settings-manager is installed. Because of this, I want to try another distro that keep simple like Slackware :) I look for the distro, read the top ten disto review at distrowatch.com. After that, I think I found a simple distro called Arch Linux.<br />Arch linux has a small ISO installer package and I dowload for the i686 architecture and install on my laptop. It's installation time is amazingly very short! Just 5-10 minutes and rebooting....... So, the Arch boot in the text mode and yes.... there are no desktop environment at all. damn..... And then I try to install KDE as the desktop environment with <br /><pre>pacman -S kde</pre>Okay.. I wait for a century to finish the download process since the internet connection is slow. Finally after KDE installed, I can start exploring Arch with more comfortable. The KDE here is version 4.7.3. Hmm... 1..2...3... It's like another Slackware.. ;) I install the applicatons that I need and not forget to install codecs too for listening to my mp3 music file.. yeahh!! Hmmm.. looks like everything complete now. So, I can continue my journey with Arch.... installing developer tools that I need and start coding again! :D You should try it too!</div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Georgian Cuisine</div>
<div class='content'>
Thanks<br /><br />i like your blog ))</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>kavita</div>
<div class='content'>
Thanks for sharing the knowledge.For the basic knowledge visit below link.I got deeply and basic knowledge through it.<br /><br />http://letsbeginlinux.blogspot.com/</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Budi Ariyanto</div>
<div class='content'>
Yeah you&#39;re right. I don&#39;t know it at first deal with Arch. But now my system is already at the complete stage. :D Thanks for the info.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Anonymous</div>
<div class='content'>
instead of installing the whole kdem maybe you should start with a minimal one and start your customization from there.<br /><br />pacman -S kdebase</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Still Have Some Problems On Slackware 13.37, But It's OK]]></title>
    <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/still-have-some-problems-on-slackware/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-30T05:55:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2011/04/30/still-have-some-problems-on-slackware</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Slackware 13.37 is released. I have install it on my laptop too. Overall it's superb, but there's several problems that I don't know yet how to solve it :<br /><ol><li>My laptop(ASUS A42J series) have hybrid graphics(nVidia and Intel) and use nVidia Optimus Technology. Until now, there's no official plan from nVidia to support hybrid graphics switching on linux. I have check the BIOS too, but there's no option for activate the discrete graphics only. In the slackware 13.37 default packages, there are noveau, but it makes my laptop hang while entering KDE, so I must black listing it in the configuration. At all, I only can use the Intel card. Although my nVidia card cannot be activated, the 3D acceleration for running compiz (desktop effects in KDE) works smoothly with Intel. :)</li><li>I still cannot disable touch pad from X (use Fn+F9 combination keys on my laptop). So, I decide to disable it from BIOS since it often makes me do an accidental click.</li><li>Still cannot turn off laptop wireless indicator light too, but it's no big deal because the wireless device actually turned off. The problem just on the light indicator. :)</li></ol>Hopefully my problems can be solved in the future. Thanks to Patrick Volkerding and team who makes Slackware. Good job team! :)</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New Friend In My Boarding House]]></title>
    <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/new-friend-in-my-boarding-house/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-02T21:30:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2011/02/02/new-friend-in-my-boarding-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Today I have a new friend in my boarding house. He's from Bandung and work as Japanese translator. I think it's amazing since person who can understand Japanese language is rare in Indonesia. I have talk to him on first time and he share about some knowledge of Japanese culture, lifestyle and culinary. The Japanese culinary is the most part that I interested on it, like ramen, sushi, yakiniku and the others. He say he can cook it, but I'm not sure yet though.<img class="emoticon" src="http://us.i1.yimg.com/us.yimg.com/i/mesg/emoticons7/4.gif" width="18" alt="big grin" title="big grin" /> It's very interesting you know. From this conversation, I've got many new knowledges. I hope he can stay in the boarding house for a long time and maybe he can take me to Japan, at least for a vacation to Japan like he ever did. <img class="emoticon" src="http://statics.plurk.com/aabbc82c2b0dc72bfbce2f82c97a95e8.gif" width="15" alt="Evil Grin" title="Evil Grin" /></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Wagkangmakulit</div>
<div class='content'>
Japanese language is difficult but as we all know it&#39;s a big advantage to learn the language. If we go to Japan, for sure, advantage is ours. Have a great day!<br /><br />Wagkangmakulit<br /><br /><a href="http://www.computercollisioninvestigations.com/" rel="nofollow">pocket zone</a></div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Mark Lloyd Biñar</div>
<div class='content'>
It really difficult to speak Japanese Language but for sure little by little you can learn it.<br /><br /><a href="http://www.offermyoffer.com/vouchers/detail/alpharooms.com/3852" rel="nofollow">Alpha rooms</a></div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Mark Lloyd Biñar</div>
<div class='content'>
This comment has been removed by the author.</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>master reseller</div>
<div class='content'>
japanese language is very difficult, it is even difficult as compared to chinese, you&#39;ve been gifted with a great opportunity to learn this great language</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>software development</div>
<div class='content'>
japanese people are known for their dedication towards work</div>
</div>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>sim only deals</div>
<div class='content'>
Japanese language is one of difficult language, you should treat that as your great experience...</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Xorg Updates On Slackware -current]]></title>
    <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2011/02/01/xorg-updates-on-slackware-current/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-01T21:21:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2011/02/01/xorg-updates-on-slackware-current</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
Today <a href="http://www.slackware.com/changelog/current.php?cpu=i386">Slackware -current updates</a>(Feb 1 2011) makes me happy, because there's a lot of Xorg updates. Now I'm using Slackware 13.1 on my laptop and there are several problems like wireless light indicator keeps turn on even I turned it off, a lot of Fn toggle keys combination that not yet work and touch pad that cannot be turned off. I hope with the Xorg updates can fix my problems in the future when I upgrade my system to Slackware 13.2. Thanks to Robby Workman for this updates. <img class="emoticon" src="http://us.i1.yimg.com/us.yimg.com/i/mesg/emoticons7/41.gif" width="18" alt="applause" title="applause" /><div>There's also added package, xdg-user-dirs to help manage "well-known" user directories like Desktop and music folder. I cannot imagine yet how this package works, but I'm sure there is a better folder management on Slackware 13.2. I just can't wait the Slackware 13.2 to be released and upgrade my system. <img class="emoticon" src="http://statics.plurk.com/4f01bac8a707e5450307f97065ec0fa7.gif" width="30" alt="Banana Cool" title="Banana Cool" /></div></div>


<h2>Comments</h2>


<div class='comments'>
<div class='comment'>
<div class='author'>Esteban Gambino</div>
<div class='content'>
I too am patiently awaiting the release of 13.2, as my new notebook will need the latest and greatest tools available in order to function properly! No self respecting linux hacker would burn in a new machine without a fresh install of Slackware.</div>
</div>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
