<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: IDE | My Personal Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/categories/ide/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-05-22T10:34:01+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Budi Ariyanto]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Writing Python Codes Easier With PyDev]]></title>
    <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2010/12/12/writing-python-codes-easier-with-pydev/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-12T18:56:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2010/12/12/writing-python-codes-easier-with-pydev</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
After several days I'm looking for the best open source IDE for writing <a href="http://www.python.org/">Python</a> codes, I have found that <a href="http://www.eclipse.org/">Eclipse</a> or <a href="http://aptana.com/downloads/start">Aptana</a> with <a href="http://pydev.org/">PyDev</a> Extension is the best. In the beginning, PyDev has a commercial license, but since September 2009 PyDev open sourced. PyDev has a lot of features that help python developers write the codes easier(code auto completion, syntax highlighting, code folding, code snippets, auto imports, etc). In the next release, PyDev will support unit testing. <div>The runner up is <a href="http://www.geany.org/">Geany</a>. It's a lightweight general purpose editor. The syntax highlighting in Geany is great, but it's poor in auto code completion features. It only support few calltips. I recommend to use Eclipse or Aptana with PyDev. PyDev installation can be viewed on it's website.</div></div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Netbeans 7.0 Beta Now Available To Download]]></title>
    <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2010/11/20/netbeans-70-beta-now-available-to/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-20T06:58:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2010/11/20/netbeans-70-beta-now-available-to</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
This morning I go to the <a href="http://netbeans.org/">netbeans official site</a>, and I found a news that Netbeans 7.0 beta available for download. It seems netbeans 7.0 supports the HTML5 source editing, provide integration to the oracle database and new gridbag layout for improved Swing GUI development. It's a great improvement from previous netbeans release. I hope netbeans can support for CSS3 script editing too in the future. :)</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
