<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: wiki | My Personal Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/categories/wiki/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-16T18:25:14+07:00</updated>
  <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Budi Ariyanto]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Moinmoin Wiki Engine]]></title>
    <link href="http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2012/02/08/moinmoin-wiki-engine/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-08T22:15:00+07:00</updated>
    <id>http://budiariyanto.github.io/blog/2012/02/08/moinmoin-wiki-engine</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class='post'>
This is my first post at 2012. I want to get used to post articles at this blog again, beside my activities at the office. At this post, I want to share about a wiki engine that I currently interested in. It is named <a href="http://moinmo.in/" target="_blank">moinmoin</a>. It is not a new wiki engine and has already well known at world wild. This wiki engine is developed using <a href="http://python.org/" target="_blank">python</a> programming language. I love this wiki engine because this wiki engine is well documented, easy to setup, easy to use and it has many features, including but not limited to:<br /><ol><li>Easy wiki syntax.</li><li>Runs at any web server such as <a href="http://httpd.apache.org/" target="_blank">apache</a>, <a href="http://nginx.org/" target="_blank">nginx</a> and moinmoin stand alone web server(using python). But if you want to use apache or nginx, you need <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_Server_Gateway_Interface" target="_blank">wsgi</a> or <a href="http://www.fastcgi.com/drupal/" target="_blank">fast-cgi </a>module for the respective webserver. Don't use cgi since it's slow.</li><li>Macros. -- I love the macro that help create the table of contents :)</li><li>Auto numbering.</li><li>Easy leveling the depth of item/numbered list.</li><li>Private sub page.</li><li>It's content saved in plain text format. It means, save harddisk space and light weight.</li><li>Many plugins/addons. </li></ol>Currently I'm beginning to use moinmoin for works on any non-source code documentation at the office collaborate with my partners. Since it runs on web browser, everyone can read it. Trust me, it's fun. And it's even more fun if you combine moinmoin with <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/" target="_blank">dropbox</a>! :D</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
